WEB PRODUCER

Professional Profile

Over 3 years' Web Development experience, with proven background in JavaScript, HTML, XHTML, CSS and PHP Successfully managing all aspects of site development, from initial design and architecture. Demonstrated ability to complete projects in deadline-oriented environments. Talented graphic designer with excellent problem-solving skills. Able to effectively communicate with wide range of clients and coworkers. Qualifications

DHTML, XHTML, HTML, JavaScript, SQL, ASP, PHP, Visual Basic, C++, COBOL. Graphics: Photoshop, Illustrator, Dreamweaver, Adobe Acrobat. Software: Microsoft Word, Access, Excel, PowerPoint, Microsoft Project, Norton Ghost, Greenstone Digital Library. MySQL, Windows 9x, 2000/ME, XP, Vista, Windows 7, MSDOS, Linux. Flowcharting: Microsoft Visio, System Architect

Experience

02/2009 to 07/2009

Web producer C2fo Limited i1/4 Kansas City, MO

- Created the layout and design for Scient Systems using JavaScript, DHTML, HTML and CSS.
- Designed banners and Icons using Photoshop.

06/2007 to 07/2009

Web Master Bickford Senior Living i1/4 Bloomington, IL

• Maintain the IIS Web server for 4,000 daily users Synchronize the Web server with backup Web server on weekly basis using Total Commander Update the web pages using PHP, HTML, CSS and JavaScript Run statistics on monthly basis using Ezproxy for library databases being accessed Create a complete report at the end of fiscal year for Library Webserver and Library database statistics Create monthly calendar for each semester Project: Greenstone Installed Greenstone Digital Library software on a new sever for an image collection Changed the look of the page by editing macros and CSS files Updated the metadata and entered new metadata using Greenstone librarian interface Set up Greenstone librarian interface client software which helped librarians to enter and update data remotely Set up daily statistics using WUsage log file analysis for Greenstone server Project: MediaWiki Installed MediaWiki for the reference desk librarians which made it easier for them to create new pages and edit information on their own Edited the wiki, changed the logo, header, footer and navigation menu using PHP Created user accounts and set up passwords Project: Accessibility Assessed the website and made is accessible for all types of users Analyzed the site using wave webaim org to locate the accessibility errors Then added alt tags for images and captions among other things Project: Website Formatting Created a side menu for information pages giving it neater look using HTML and CSS Created a new footer by adding Library Site Search option and John Jay Logo Changed the format using Cascading Style Sheets.

01/2007 to 07/2007

Bickford Senior Living i1/4 Overland Park, KS

Installed Windows Operating system Re-imaged new and old PCs using Norton Ghost Assisted users with technical problems such as
setting up wireless network Troubleshoot and installed PCs, printers and other peripheral devices Answered help desk calls and
documented the work orders Installed patches for windows updates Cleaned the infected PCs from viruses Updated the intranet site using
the Content Management System Joomla and Dream weaver.

01/2006 to 05/2006

Orchestra Of St. Luke's i1/4 City, STATE

- Created entire relational database for their reservation system using Access and SQL Imported existing data from excel spreadsheet
 Created tables, forms and reports Created queries using SQL joins and SQL Functions Created a user friendly interface by adding form buttons and graphics Made their reservation system more efficient by letting user enter data using forms Updated the Orchestra of St.
- Luke's web page using ASP, HTML and JavaScript ACADEMIC PROJECTS GROUP PROJECTS Designed the Entity Relationship
 Diagram using Visio, created metadata and fragmented the data for an engineering firm Prepared a complete business plan for an advertising
 agency including business cards, brochure and website Access Project: Created a relational database for a security firm as a term project
 using Access database Normalized the data and set relationships Created data entry form and reports Created switchboard using macros
 Wrote weekly reports and documented the whole project.

Education

2006

Bachelors of Technology : Computer Systems New York City College of Technology $i\frac{1}{4}$ City , State GPA: Summa Cum Laude GPA: 3.93 Computer Systems Summa Cum Laude GPA: 3.93

Database System Design Web Design Design of Microcomputers Databases Web design and implementation Design of Distributed Databases Web programming Data Warehousing Installing and maintaining web servers Local Area Networks Advanced Single-LAN concepts Introduction to LAN Connectivity LAN-Internet Connection

A's New York City College of Technology i1/4 City, State

2004

Associate: Applied Science Computer Information Systems GPA: Departmental Award for highest GPA in Computers Systems Department, Dean's list *Scholarships: Was awarded scholarship for three semesters from National Science Foundation. *Volunteered as a chemistry tutor in Fall 2002 Applied Science Computer Information Systems Departmental Award for highest GPA in Computers Systems Department, Dean's list *Scholarships: Was awarded scholarship for three semesters from National Science Foundation. *Volunteered as a chemistry tutor in Fall 2002 Affiliations

Muslim Students Association Member, Student Government Association Secretary and Senator (2004 and 2005)

ACADEMIC, Adobe Acrobat, Dreamweaver, Dream weaver, Photoshop, advertising, ASP, agency, backup, banners, brochure, business cards, business plan, C++, Cascading Style Sheets, COBOL, Content Management, CSS, client, data entry, Databases, Database, Data Warehousing, DHTML, editing, edit, Flowcharting, forms, Graphics, help desk, HTML, PHP, IIS, Illustrator, image, JavaScript, Local Area Networks, LAN, layout and design, librarian, Linux, Logo, macros, Microcomputers, Access, Access database, Excel, Windows Operating system, PowerPoint, Microsoft Project, Microsoft Visio, Windows 7, Windows 9, windows, 2000, Microsoft Word, MSDOS, MySQL, navigation, network, Norton Ghost, page, printers, Programming, relational database, spreadsheet, SQL, statistics, switchboard, System Design, System Architect, tables, Troubleshoot, Visio, Vista, Visual Basic, Web programming, web servers, Web server, Web Design, Website, web pages, web page, XHTML Additional Information

• Honors and Achievements: Tau phi sigma, Dean's List.